### Name Mohammed Issa

Address: Reading England

Mobile: 07404941366 Email: mi9036648@gmail.com

Portfolio: LinkedIn:

#### **Personal Profile**

As an Electrical and Electronic Engineer, SDET Software Automation Tester, and AI Automation Tester, I am capable of analysing engineering problems, evaluating and recommending alternatives. I have a strong understanding of computer hardware and software, as well as knowledge of programming languages such as Python, Java, and C++. I am also well-versed in automation tools, such as Selenium and TestNG. I am experienced in developing test plans, creating test cases, and executing tests. In addition to being adaptable, I have a quick learn. Currently a student at Just IT software bootcamp.

My goal is to work as a Software Developer while acquiring the necessary skills and experience. I excel in challenging environments, where I can tackle problems and discover optimal solutions.

#### **Key Skills**

#### **Technical Skills**

- Al Automation Programming using Python & LangChain
- Software Automation Testing, Python and Java frameworks
- Advanced Linux knowledge
- AWS, Advanced AWS Services.
- C, C++, C#, and GoLang at intermediate level
- HTML, CSS, React JS, Node JS, Django at intermediate level.
- DevOps, CICD Jenkins, SonarQube, Jfrog Artifactory, Docker, Teraform, Ansible, and Kubernetes.
- Bash Scripting, and PowerShell.
- SOL databases, and NoSal Mongodb.
- ML and DS Frameworks Pandas, PyTorch, NumPy, Keras and TensorFlow.
- OS Familiarity: Linux, Windows, and MacOS.

#### **Soft Skills**

Soft skills are crucial for automation testers, enhancing their technical capabilities. Key skills include effective communication for collaboration, strong problem-solving and critical thinking for issue resolution, and attention to detail for thorough testing. Adaptability and creativity are important for learning new tools and developing innovative solutions. Additionally, teamwork, time management, and conflict resolution skills help testers contribute effectively to group goals and navigate challenges within the team.

#### **Training and Education**

**10/2024-Present** 

Just IT Training Ltd, London
Digital Skills Bootcamp: Software Development
A twelve-week intensive bootcamp covering the fundamentals of Software Development.

Development of HTML, Introduction to HTML/JavaScript/CSS, Developed a web-based product, Database design, Built a product using Python

09/2006-07/2012

University Of Nottingham, Nottingham UK
BEng Electrical and Electronic Engineering

#### **Core Modules:**

**Languages:** Signals and Systems, Electromagnetism, HTML, Circuits and Systems, C, C++, Java, Power Electronics and Power Systems, Telecommunications, Control systems design, Electronics design, VLSI, Micro controllers, DC motors and ladder logics, microwaves, and image processing.

**Final Year Project:** "Satelite Communication" – Using Advanced Design Systems ADS for microwaves, to design a satelite communication system project, taking acurate mesurements usting smith chart. And also an android project using Java and weather api to search for weather in any UK city, where the application was a web based.

09/2005-07/2006 Lambeth College & London Southbank University

UK, Vauxhall Centre Access Course:

**Electrical and Electronic Engineering** 

MM/2002-MM/2003 East London ITEC, East London, Forest

Gate

ICT Level 2 Diploma: Computer Systems Support.

#### **Employment History**

#### 03/2022-07/2023 Automation Tester Web & Al

**Infosys**, Canary Wharf, London. Also while being with Infosys, worked for a **British Petroleum** (BP) Project.

- Duties included Automation testing of various web application projects, mainly banking applications.
- Using different frameworks such as python, java and C#
- APIs and automation testing tools such as jMeter.

# MM/2019-MM/2020 Help Desk Engineer Precept IT, Belfast UK, Also while being at Precept worked for Inteling Belfast

- Duties ranged from setup, configure, and install softwares, AD, Remote troubleshooting.
- VPNs, Printers, creating company user emails, unlock & reset passwords, install certificates.
- Issues in general, and repair PCs, Laptops & configure according to a company user requirement.
- Annual leave cover at Intelling, covering Engineering responsibilities for their Engineer while being on holiday.

## 12/2019-03/2019 Work placement Belfast Metroploitan College DepT, Belfast UK

Web development training Microsoft technologies, MVC, CSS, HTML5, Bootstrap and Razor Pages. This job ended due to the pandemic in 2019

#### **Interests, Hobbies and Achievements**

**Hobbies:** Televised Snooker game, technology related projects.

#### **Additional Info:**

Engineering Membership: The Institution of Electrical and Electronic Engineering IEEE USA. And AWS Cloud Practitioner Certified at TechTalent Academy UK 2021. Fluent in Arabic Language, speaking, reading and writing.

#### References available upon request